<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://sorbet.org/blog</id>
    <title>Sorbet Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-07-27T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://sorbet.org/blog"/>
    <subtitle>The best place to stay up-to-date with the latest Sorbet news and events.</subtitle>
    <logo>https://sorbet.org/img/sorbet-logo-white-sparkles.svg</logo>
    <rights>© 2026 Stripe</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tapioca is the recommended way to generate RBIs for Sorbet]]></title>
        <id>https://sorbet.org/blog/2022/07/27/srb-tapioca.html</id>
        <link href="https://sorbet.org/blog/2022/07/27/srb-tapioca.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-27T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we’re excited to announce that the Sorbet team officially recommends using Shopify’s <a href="https://github.com/Shopify/tapioca">Tapioca</a> gem for RBI generation in projects that use Sorbet. Tapioca takes the place of the <code>srb rbi</code> family of commands, which as of today are officially in maintenance mode. Sorbet itself remains in active development.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jake Zimmerman</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/jez_io</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open-sourcing the Sorbet VS Code Extension]]></title>
        <id>https://sorbet.org/blog/2022/01/06/open-sourcing-sorbet-vscode.html</id>
        <link href="https://sorbet.org/blog/2022/01/06/open-sourcing-sorbet-vscode.html"/>
        <updated>2022-01-06T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to announce that Stripe’s VS Code extension for Sorbet is now <a href="https://github.com/sorbet/sorbet/tree/master/vscode_extension">open source</a>. We’ve designed Sorbet to be used in editors from Day 1—For the past two years, Sorbet has exposed a flag (<code>--lsp</code>) that starts Sorbet in <a href="https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/">Language Server Protocol</a> (LSP) mode. In this mode, Sorbet can respond to many LSP requests, like Go To Definition, Find All References, Autocomplete, and more.</p>
<p>With this release, we’re making it even easier to take advantage of these LSP features when working with Sorbet in VS Code. We hope that this extension takes some of the guess work out of how to configure and use Sorbet’s LSP mode.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sorbet Compiler: An experimental, ahead-of-time compiler for Ruby]]></title>
        <id>https://sorbet.org/blog/2021/07/30/open-sourcing-sorbet-compiler.html</id>
        <link href="https://sorbet.org/blog/2021/07/30/open-sourcing-sorbet-compiler.html"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past year, the <a href="https://sorbet.org/">Sorbet</a> team has been working on an experimental, ahead-of-time compiler for Ruby, powered by Sorbet and LLVM. Today we’re sharing the source code for it. It lives alongside the existing code for Sorbet on GitHub, mostly in the <code>compiler/</code> folder:</p>
<p>→ <a href="https://github.com/sorbet/sorbet/tree/master/compiler/">https://github.com/sorbet/sorbet/tree/master/compiler/</a></p>
<p>We want to be clear up front: the code is nowhere near ready for external use right now, but we welcome you to read the code and give us feedback on our approach!</p>
<p>We teased this a few weeks back in a tweet, which drew a fair bit of attention, and also a lot of questions:</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Types in Ruby 3, RBS, and Sorbet]]></title>
        <id>https://sorbet.org/blog/2020/07/30/ruby-3-rbs-sorbet.html</id>
        <link href="https://sorbet.org/blog/2020/07/30/ruby-3-rbs-sorbet.html"/>
        <updated>2020-07-30T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday Square <a href="https://developer.squareup.com/blog/the-state-of-ruby-3-typing/">posted an article</a> to their blog introducing <a href="https://github.com/ruby/rbs">RBS</a> (Ruby Signature), a type syntax format for Ruby 3.</p>
<p>We’d like to take a second to speak to how RBS relates to Sorbet. The short version: Sorbet will happily incorporate RBS as a way to specify type annotations, in addition to the existing syntax Sorbet supports. Stripe still has a very strong commitment to Sorbet’s continued progress and success. While the Ruby core team has been working on syntax, we’ve been working on features that build on top of that syntax.</p>
<p>With that in mind, I’d love to start a discussion of some of the finer points of what this announcement means for Ruby, and for Sorbet.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jake Zimmerman</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/jez_io</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Sorbet 0.5]]></title>
        <id>https://sorbet.org/blog/2019/12/20/announcing-sorbet-0.5.html</id>
        <link href="https://sorbet.org/blog/2019/12/20/announcing-sorbet-0.5.html"/>
        <updated>2019-12-20T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we’re excited to celebrate six months since Sorbet’s open source release!</p>
<p>Sorbet is a fast, powerful type checker for Ruby developed by Stripe and an ever-growing community of contributors. You can <a href="https://sorbet.run">try it online</a> or <a href="https://sorbet.org/docs/adopting">set it up in your project</a> today. Sorbet gradually integrates into existing Ruby projects. With Sorbet, people writing Ruby gain more confidence in their changes and get faster feedback while iterating.</p>
<p>At this milestone, we’d like to take a look back on what’s happened since the first public release of Sorbet, and what’s coming in the future.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jake Zimmerman</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/jez_io</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open-sourcing Sorbet: a fast, powerful type checker for Ruby]]></title>
        <id>https://sorbet.org/blog/2019/06/20/open-sourcing-sorbet.html</id>
        <link href="https://sorbet.org/blog/2019/06/20/open-sourcing-sorbet.html"/>
        <updated>2019-06-20T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to announce that Sorbet is now <a href="https://github.com/sorbet/sorbet">open source</a> and you can try it today. Sorbet is a fast, powerful type checker designed for Ruby. It scales to codebases with millions of lines of code and can be adopted incrementally.</p>
<p>We designed Sorbet to be used at Stripe, where the vast majority of our code is written in Ruby. We’ve spent the last year and a half developing and adopting Sorbet internally, and we’re finally confident that Sorbet is not just an experimental, internal project—we’re ready to share Sorbet with the entire Ruby community. In fact, we’ve had more than 30 companies beta test Sorbet and provide feedback.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[State of Sorbet Spring 2019]]></title>
        <id>https://sorbet.org/blog/2019/05/16/state-of-sorbet-spring-2019.html</id>
        <link href="https://sorbet.org/blog/2019/05/16/state-of-sorbet-spring-2019.html"/>
        <updated>2019-05-16T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stripe uses Ruby extensively<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup>. It’s the main language we use to build the business logic behind our APIs, and our Ruby codebase is on the order of millions of lines of code. At that scale and with our expected rapid growth rate two things are true: 1) we need all the tooling help we can get to understand and modify that much code, and 2) a total rewrite in a statically typed language would be a massive undertaking.</p>
<!-- prettier-ignore-start -->
<!-- prettier-ignore-end -->
<p>With that in mind, in October 2017 a small team of engineers conceived of building Sorbet, a gradual static type system for Ruby. Static type systems look for certain classes of potential errors without running your code. A gradual static type system allows you to gradually add static typing, leaving some parts of your code purely dynamically typed. Other examples of gradual static type systems that have been added onto existing dynamically typed languages are <a href="https://flow.org/">Flow</a> and <a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/">TypeScript</a> for Javascript, and <a href="https://hacklang.org/">Hack</a> for PHP. In this post, we’d like to give a brief update about what we’ve been working on, and where we’re going next.</p>
<hr class="footnotes-sep">
<section class="footnotes">
<ol class="footnotes-list">
<li id="fn1"  class="footnote-item"><p>We also use plenty of of other languages including Go for
infrastructure tasks, Scala for data wrangling, and JavaScript for client-side
work. <a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Iry</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/jamesiry</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>